All right, welcome to the Tier One
podcast. And today I'm very pleased to
announce that I've got David Holt, owner
of Holt Law Firm. And David, I'd like
you to tell us a little bit about
yourself. Uh today's topic is of course
going to be the world of peptides. And
I'm hoping that you can shed some light
on the information or therefore
misinformation regarding peptides. So
once again, a pleasure to have you,
David.
>> Hey, thanks for having me. Really
excited to be here. Pick the new year
off, right? Yeah, I'm David Holt. Go by
DJ, transactional healthcare business
attorney. Work a lot and only with
healthcare providers. And so have gotten
a lot of questions over the last year in
2025 about peptides, what's legal,
what's not legal, what if I am doing it
anyway type questions. And so I'm
excited to explore more as to what the
law actually says with you.
>> Well, let's uh get right into it. as I
you know I research I'm on the health
and wellness practice so I do a lot of
research a lot of literature reviews and
of course every day I get a question on
peptides multiple questions on peptides
from patients and I used to take the
time to write a extensive you know
letter back to them but now I just
typically refer your website to them and
specifically what you've written on your
website because the information I found
there was extremely valuable and I want
everyone to understand that this is not
a podcast about peptides as far as good
or bad. This is not what it's about.
It's simply about trying to shed light
on the truth about the prescribing of
peptides by providers and the risks that
they may be taking in doing so. And so,
David, if you can uh kind of lead us
into this u you know on your website and
I'm going to this will be attached to
our to our podcast of course, but the
unregulated world of peptides, what you
need to know before you inject. Can you
kind of lead us through? I'll just start
as a highlevel overview assuming we know
you know very little about peptides and
so um the the United States does not
make it easy uh in my opinion as an
attorney you know trying to explain this
day in and day out as to what we can and
can't do. So I will I will say that
right out of the gate. What I tried to
do here, and I'm sure we could share it
in the show notes, is state specifically
what the FDA or the federal government
has said we can and cannot do. You know,
right on the website, straight bulletin
guidance from the FDA. And the FDA in
the United States has full authority to
regulate and say what can and cannot be
used in humans. Period. Um, some people
may not like that. Some people may um
not be thrilled about that, but those
are the rules. Um
high level uh effectively a peptide such
as you know BPC157 or you know a whole
other list of peptides, it needs to be
on what's called a a final bulk list or
um it has to be an FDA approved drug.
And a lot of these are not yet all the
way FDA approved, which therefore means
it's then illegal to compound inside of
the United States. So I'll say that
again. If the FDA hasn't either put it
on one of its list or giving it given it
a blessing, I'll just paraphrase, then
it is illegal to compound in the United
States. So then everyone, you know,
usually says, "Well, then how are all
these other providers doing it?" Or,
"How are all these peptides making their
way into gyms and, you know, shipping to
my front door and and things like that?"
To which, you know, I I say, "Well, I
don't have all of the facts, but I could
make some educated guesses on how that
might be happening." I will say this.
Um, first off, as a licensed attorney, I
take my marching orders from federal
law, state law, and that's it. You know,
I I can talk about what it says if there
are exceptions, but if the exceptions
don't exist, that's where my advice and
and the party would be over. But I will
say this, the FDA has their hands full
with a lot of stuff right now as we move
into 2026
enforcement of uh pharmacies as well as
the providers themselves. I just don't
think that there is currently the
enforcement priority and power for them
to be able to do so. But that does not
make it legal. So, an analogy I would
give is uh I was, you know, driving on
the highway today. Everyone on that
highway was going, you know, probably 10
to 15 over. I'm not going to say whether
I was going 10 to 15 over, but you know,
there just aren't a lot of cops on the
highway. And so, not a lot of people get
pulled over. that doesn't make it legal,
but uh I I would use that analogy to a
small degree as to what I'm seeing
happening in the current market just
with how many people are landing on, you
know, my the articles that I put out
plus the questions that I'm getting. Uh
so I'll I'll pause there. I know that's
a long- winded answer, but um on the
blog, what I try to go through, and it's
very confusing. I I did not set this
system up. I just comment on it. There
are a few different things that that
happen and I'll try and paraphrase them
without getting too technical. And so
there's what's there's there what are
called compounded drugs which are
technically we'll just say unapproved
new drugs but they got a little legal
pass because they met certain
requirements by the FDA. So that's a
mouthful right there, right? Why can't
we just have yes or no? Well, you know,
it's it's on its way to a yes and a
potential approval. But in the meantime,
the FDA is giving it a classification.
So the first type of compounding or
traditional compounding would be uh
503A.
And so this is this regulates pharmacies
that compound medications for individual
identified uh patients and um there's a
valid prescription, right? Okay, good.
That that kind of makes sense. And
thosearmacies are primarily going to be
overseen by the local pharmacy boards.
Okay, that I can kind of follow with
that. Then we got these uh 503b, so not
A but E. And those would be outsourcing
facilities. Effectively what they do is
they allow a large bulk batch of you
know patient specific prescriptions to
be manufactured and then sell for office
use at the local you know clinic
hospital. Um they have to follow I think
you mentioned um CGMP guidelines or um
the good manufacturing practices. That's
a lot stricter than 503A. So in order to
ship a bulk peptide to a provider, you
got to meet this very specific uh list
of requirements. Um there are also other
peptides like BPC57 where the FDA has
got gone even further and said there is
no specific human use that's approved at
this time. That that may change in the
future. Therefore, not allowed for human
use. And so providers will say, well,
okay, uh there's clinical and then
there's uh research. So research is a
known exception to that rule. Well, you
know, research has a very specific
framework for how it's done in the
United States. And just saying that
something is for research, but then
handing it over to a patient for you as
a doctor hypothetically would not only
be putting your professional license at
jeopardy, but you're also exposing
yourself. Um, and I say this with
respect to plaintiffs attorneys out
there, you know, the personal injury
attorneys.
They have now basically unlimited access
to you because you technically violated
federal law. So, you violated law. Any
damages? We have unlimited reign over
you. So, high level, that's what's going
on. Um, I know that was a mouthful, so
I'll pause there.
>> It's excellent information. And let
let's go with that a little bit. Um, so
one thing that some of the prescribers
may not understand or may not realize is
their malpractice policies, malpractice
insurance. Now, uh, Rick Collins, good
friend of mine. He's a very well-known
attorney in the United States that deals
with, um, uh, performance-enhancement,
uh, issues, uh, people that get arrested
or get in trouble for
performance-enhancement drugs. But, uh,
Rick is very knowledgeable in in that in
that area. But I specifically asked Rick
about peptides and, uh, Rick looked
right at me. He's a, you know, a defense
attorney, and he said, "Keith, whatever
you do, never prescribe peptides." I'm
like, "I don't plan on it, Rick, but
why?" He goes because if a if a patient
has a problem with it, if they have an
issue, they blame it on the peptide.
It's indefensible. I cannot defend you.
No one can. That struck home. And and
once again, this is not a uh this is not
a tyrate against BPC 157. It's about the
legalities of prescribing as provider.
We're trying to pro protect the
providers with this podcast today. So, I
did contact as many malpractice uh
insurers as I could before our podcast
today. Not a single malpractice provider
covers non-FDA approved drugs or
research chemicals or peptides like
we're talking about that are on the do
not compound list. Not one. So, anybody
that literally is accused of uh given a
peptide that may have caused a problem
to a patient, they will have no defense
and their practice policy will not cover
them. And those and as you know,
defending yourself can run into the tens
if not hundreds of thousands of dollars
at times. All right. So that's that's
the that's the one issue that that's
very concerning is is just that alone.
And so a lot of our listeners, I see
this on uh the social media as well.
They'll say, "Well, it's just the FDA.
They're just, you know, they just don't
want you to have things that work."
Well, uh you know, whether I agree or
disagree with that statement, you know,
I'm not a big fan of FDA, but
nonetheless, the FDA
is trying to look after the uh the the
health of the individuals. And and what
I mean by that is that look, in order
for us to prescribe a drug, an FDA
approved drug, we have to have USPI
information, which is prescribing
information, the package insert that we
get as physicians, and those are based
off of randomized control trials in
humans. So they develop so we develop
this prescribing information for these
peptides and non-FDA approved and we
don't have any of that information. And
what is literally involved with an FDA
approved drug? This is what is required
in order for us to be able to prescribe
it legally. You have to have certain
information and this is the information.
You have to have a boxed warning. You
have to have a section of indications
and usage, dosage and administration,
dosage forms and strengths,
contraindications, warnings and
precautions, adverse reactions, drug
interactions, use in specific population
such as pregnancy, lactation, uh females
and male reproductive potential,
pediatric use, geriatric use, drug abuse
and dependence, overdoses, description,
clinical pharmarmacology, mechanism of
action, pharmacodnamics, phicokinetics,
pharmaccogenomics,
imogenicity,
nonclinical toxicology and then clinical
studies. Those are all part of the
package inserts we have for the drugs
that we prescribe every day, even when
we use them off label. We have none of
that information for BPC1257 or CJC
1295, you name it. None of those that
are on the do not compound list. And
that's why the FDA has not approved it
for for human uh consumption. Do you
have anything to add to that, David?
>> Yeah, 100% on the malpractice. I'll
start there. So, that's the biggest one.
you any event and uh if you've ever been
through a patient complaint or a medical
malpractice allegation, a lot of that um
can become a he said, she said, you
know, medical record uh is the best we
can do. But again, uh your malpractice
carrier would not cover it because you
are not following the law. So you have
prescribed or you've broken the law in
your administration of or your practice
of medicine. Therefore, that's an
excluded event. Just like if I
committed, you know, legal malpractice,
but I knew that I was doing something
wrong, right? My my malpractice carrier
would say, well, that's excluded, right?
You uh it's the same reason why some uh
well, why most policies don't cover
intentional tors. Like, I can't just go
around and punch people and then expect
my insurance company to pay the bill.
like there are things that are excluded.
This would be one of them. So, you'd
have to pay out of pocket. I would agree
that $100,000 would be a good day for
some of those personal injury attorneys,
especially medical malpractice or sorry,
um medical malpractice plaintiffs
attorneys. And the reason that
plaintiff's attorneys like this is that
unlike, you know, maybe a slip and fall
case where you actually have to kind of
prove, you know, well, was that a
reasonable standard of care? Right here,
they just say unapproved peptide,
therefore law broken, therefore all
damages that result, right? So, we're
really only arguing about damages, which
is never where you want to be as a
provider. On top of that, now we're
probably getting the attention of the
local medical board. Right now, you
know, inadvertently us having to deal
with that patient complaint. I wouldn't
be surprised if they also put, you know,
a little complaint in with the medical
board. You know, I won't comment on
whether that's a good strategy from the
plaintiff's perspective. I'm on the
provider side, but now not only are you
paying out damages and dealing with this
patient and their attorney that's coming
at you, but now you're also fending off
a a complaint from the medical board for
which I don't think you're going to have
a great defense. I'll even go one step
further. Um, and I wanted to make sure I
got this right, but um, in Ohio this
year, they actually um, the board of
pharmacy
um, suspended a license of a effectively
a medical spa. And they did this by just
going in looking at some of the labeling
and then saying, "Hey, this is according
to our rules ad." And effectively,
they're just kind of drawing upon FDA
rules. Now simply saying the FDA is
overburdened and you know the state
isn't going to do anything. Medical
boards, boards ofarmacies are starting
to get involved. Also in New York and
New Jersey specifically for you know
well peptides but set in a different
way. It's being regulated for minors. So
we're already starting to see a wave of
state regulation come in. I actually
think to go you know another step
further on on what you were saying. your
biggest risk and some of the videos we
were watching earlier, you know, I don't
have all the facts. I can't comment on
their situations, but I think actually
your biggest risk now is the FTC or the
Federal Trade Commission. So, we have
the FDA. Okay, that's one federal
agency. Now, we have the FTC. The FTC is
generally in charge of regulating how
advertising and how things are
represented to consumers. a consumer in
this situation being a patient. So if I
have a website or a real on a social
media platform saying that something is
pharma grade or or misleading as to
whether it's legal to to use or not, the
FD the FDC has public record of you
saying something and the FDC under
federal rules does not mess around in
terms of cease and desist as well as
fines. And they're also allowed in some
situations not just to go after you
civil civil, right? So, okay, a fine
season to say stop doing that. You know,
money is one thing, but criminal charges
as well, which is not never a good place
to be.
>> Well, do you mind if we, since you
referred to the videos, there are
YouTube shorts that anybody can go look
at. There are hundreds of them probably,
but do you mind if we play those videos?
So,
>> Sure. Yeah,
>> I'll watch them. When my patients get
peptides from me, they come from a
licensed FDA registered compounding
pharmacy or from pharmaceutical grade
suppliers that have voluntarily had all
of their products independently tested
and verified for sterility and potency.
More importantly, I discuss the
treatment plan, including proper dosing
based on the medical literature, and I
pair the right peptide for your specific
goal. Peptides are powerful, but they're
only as effective as the precision
behind how they're used. So whether your
goal is to heal, lose weight, grow
muscle, or just live longer, remember
the peptide isn't the magic. The
science, safety, and supervision behind
the peptide is. Here's the part most
people fail to understand. And this
part's the critical part. When I started
prescribing peptides about say 15 years
ago or so, they were thought of as
something kind of fringe that only
compounding made and they had to be
administered via subcutaneous injection.
And then about 10 years ago, the FDA
began very strict oversight ofarmacies
that compounded peptides and
medications. And that's why a lot of
peptides now, you're going to see online
on some pop-up website that says for
research use only or not for human
consumption. And what that really means
is they're not regulated. There's no FDA
to enforce testing for purity or
sterility. So when someone orders
peptides off a random website, they're
taking on major risks. Is this peptide
even real? Is it 5 milligrams? or maybe
it's only 3 milligrams. Or worse, what
if the peptide's not sterile and you
inject it and now you're injecting
bacteria into your system? Yes, these
are injectable medications that go
directly into your body. So, sterility
and quality control are non-negotiable.
When my patients get peptides from me,
they come from a licensed FDA registered
compounding pharmacy or from
pharmaceutical grade suppliers that have
voluntarily had all of their products
independently tested and verified for
stability and potency.
>> Dr. Dr. Hod, your board certified
anti-aging and regenerative medicine MD
here to talk to you guys about something
very important, which is the difference
between pharmaceutical grade or pharma
grade peptides and research grade
peptides. So pharmagra peptides are
always going to be from a licensed
pharmacy. Research peptides are going to
be from a research facility. Pharmagra
peptides are regulated by the FDA, the
pharmacy board they are licensed under
as well as the DEA, whereas research
peptides are unregulated because they
are not meant for human use. They're
meant for research purposes only. Pharma
grade peptides have to be prescribed by
a licensed physician in the state that
you are getting them prescribed into.
Research peptides can be given out by
anybody including naturopaths,
chiropractors, therapists, health
coaches, fitness trainers, influencers,
the guy at the gym, or even you can get
them yourself through the gray market
online by yourself. Pharmarmacray
peptides require strict lab testing
which is regulated under cgmp and USP
sterile pharmacy guideline rules meaning
that they have to be thoroughly tested
for purity as well as for bacterial
endotoxin to make sure they're safe that
you don't develop any serious
life-threatening reactions just like
every other pharmaceutical that we have.
There's strict rules that regulate and
govern pharmagra peptides. Research
grade peptides do not have these rules.
There are some research peptide
companies that are doing cgmp testing. I
would recommend those over the ones that
aren't. But just keep in mind this still
is not a requirement because they're
research grade or they're meant for
research purposes only. Pharmagra
peptides because there is a licensed
physician obtaining the medication from
a licensed pharmacy and a physician
patient relationship. There has to be an
informed consent to take place which
means the physician has to talk to the
patient about safety risks and benefits.
Actually discuss and create an informed
consent to see if the patient is not at
increased risk and if the patient is
then this needs to be discussed with the
patient. With research grade peptides,
people are able to get them without the
patient physician risk and benefit
stratification and assessment. So,
pharma grade peptides come to you from
the pharmacy on ice generally in a vial
that's reconstituted ready to inject and
doesn't need to be mixed. Research
peptides come to you generally in a
liophalized powder which either you have
to mix yourself or the person giving
them to you has to mix them for you or
they might give them to you in
pre-filled syringes. Generally, these
would come as a powder that needs to be
mixed. So, make sure you ask these
questions when somebody's giving you
peptides. Are these research grade? Are
they pharmaceutical grade? For your own
long-term health and your own knowledge,
it's important to know if it is research
grade. Look for that third-party
testing. See if it's from a CGMP
certified facility. Look at the third
party testing. See if it's pure and also
see if other people have used that same
company, have a good experience with it.
If you want to know more about our
pharmaceutical grade offerings for
peptides, all of them are pharmaceutical
grade and all of them are meeting all
the criteria that I mentioned on this
side of the table. But it's important to
know what you're taking so you can make
the right appropriate actionable changes
in your health and the safe changes that
you need to make to optimize your health
the most.
>> I don't know the exact legal setup and
all the facts with these uh individuals
but there is only one set of rules. Uh
they are the federal rules that are
administered by the FDA. Right? So
suggesting that something is, you know,
pharmaceutical grade versus um intended
for research only, it it misses how
things are legally classified and I
think is slightly misleading. The you're
either approved or you're not. Okay,
that's step one for the FDA. And then in
unapproved, you basically get placed
into various different uh well, we're on
our way to approval. It's okay, you
know, here's the public bulletin or holy
cow, stay away from this one, like
BPC157.
So, uh, there is I mean there's no
secret that there is a lot of money and
there are a lot of consumers for
peptides period. I will just say that
and acknowledge that because I think
that's why there's a lot of pressure
here. And I don't think uh consumers or
doctors are thrilled that the FDA is
saying what it's saying. I have, you
know, no real input on that. But that
doesn't mean that you can supersede the
FDA or argue with science, uh, you know,
and and say, well, you know, best
interests of the patient type arguments.
And I also don't like the fact that
there aren't any qualifiers on these
videos. So, I would have liked to have
seen more of a reference to, well, if
you want to know more, please visit the
FDA uh website and then boom, boom, here
is the current list because I think that
would give a lot more context. Um, how
they actually got a hold of these
peptide compounded peptides. I'm I'm I'm
just going to assume we're referencing
BPC57, but that may not be the case. Uh,
that's my main question back to the
video uh producers. So, uh, gray area,
yellow area, I have a lot of questions.
Period.
>> No respectable compounding pharmacy is
is compounding peptides. None. And that
because I know that it's illegal to do
so. Uh, so the ones the ones that these
doctors are promoting are illegally
obtained. It's it's not even a gray
area. We both, you know, know that. So,
a couple of things to piggyback on what
you've said. So, I do think uh I hope
I'm going to be wrong on this, but I do
think you're going to see uh a wave of
lawsuits and it's going to be a new
avenue for pliff attorneys because once
again, this been going on for a year or
two or more now. And any problems that a
person may have that's going to blame it
on that peptide, no defense for that
prescriber. None at all. And that's a
dangerous spot to be in. And also, you
mentioned the medical board. So, before
our podcast today, I'm licensed in
several states. So I did contact some
representatives of several medical
boards and asked them specifically about
not FDA approved peptides for instance.
Once again not standard of care. You're
risking your medical license suspension
or revoke or being revoked by doing so.
I don't know why anybody works so hard
to you know to get their medical license
and degree and then willing to take such
a risk to lose it. It just makes no
sense to me. Um but nonetheless it is
happening and I can't say this enough.
This is not anti-eptides. Uh, you know,
GLP ones are wonderful. There's some
wonderful peptides out there. FDA
approved ones that are miracle drugs,
but we're talking specifically about the
non-FDA approved ones uh that the FDA
has put on the do not compound list. So,
let me read from your from your website
real quick uh just so they can get the
you know that the straightforward
response. So, you you in bold print you
say, "Can physicians prescribe non-FDA
approved drugs?" And the answer is the
short answer is no. Physicians may
legally prescribe FDA approved drugs for
either their approved uses or for other
off label uses supported by medical
judgment. But if a drug has never
received FDA approval for any
indication, it cannot be prescribed,
dispensed, or marketed for patient care.
Doing so is considered the use of an
unapproved new drug which is prohibited
under federal law and it can expose
providers to FDA enforcement, state
medical board discipline, and liability
risk for providers. The critical
takeaway is that administering or
prescribing a substance classified as an
unapproved new drug is a violation of
federal law. This category includes many
popular peptides and biologics marketed
as research chemicals which lack FDA
approval for any therapeutic use.
Engaging in such activity can be deemed
unprofessional conduct by state medical
boards and may attract federal scrutiny.
I don't think you could have said it any
more clearly in your in your in your
website. I don't know what more we can
really say on the subject.
>> Uh it took me a while to write. it
succinctly. So, thank you. I appreciate
it. It's not easy to
>> to write it. It seems like it. It's uh
I'll go one step further too to your
previous um because I see a lot of the
loopholes that people believe are
exceptions is just treating yourself as
a health coach. So, I'm not using my
medical license. I'm actually now, you
know, magically relabeled myself quickly
as a a coach. Um, I will say to this,
uh, I will say this, um, it would be
like, uh, somebody saying, "Oh, I'm not
an attorney now. I'm just a lay person,
but I'm still going to give legal
advice, right?" That the FDA looks down
to the intended use and what is actually
being done. They're not dumb. And on top
of that, unlicensed practice of
medicine, right, or unlicensed practice
of X is usually
uh also again a criminal offense as
opposed to a civil offense, which is a
bigger is a big deal. Damages, money is
one thing. Jail
>> a very different thing or the threat of
jail. And so, um, magically saying that
you're a health coach or well, actually,
I'm not prescribing, I'm just
recommending or educating
you need to be very careful in your
belief system that that is a legal
loophole and now you're out of the reign
of the FDA now that you're not
prescribing. So,
>> I just want to hammer that home, too.
I'm so glad you brought that up because
what we're seeing in this space
especially are a lot of non-medical
trained individuals that want to use the
word as coaching and you hire them for
coaching but what they're actually doing
is an interpreting your labs
recommending dosage of different medic
uh different hormones for instance or
even other medications and they are
actually practicing medicine without a
license and uh no matter how many
disclaimers they have no matter how many
you know consent forms you may sign
they're not worth the paper they're
written on. Once you take money,
interpret labs, give medical advice,
especially with dosage or you know
adding or subtracting certain drugs, you
are practicing medicine and it is a
criminal offense. It's it's a felony in
most states if not all. And so you're
seeing that a lot uh presently in our
space as well.
>> Yeah. Uh not a client of mine and uh not
you know uh but I can comment in general
terms. Uh there was a a matter where uh
basically a doctor um was using the
health coach defense, we'll call it, and
uh the medical board when they received
a complaint and that lawyer uh made the
argument, well actually this you you
don't have jurisdiction because he is
not using his medical license. And the
medical board effectively their response
was, you're right. This is unlicensed
practice of medicine. we're going to
refer it to the attorney general's
office for criminal prosecution. So, it
was really a slap in the face when they
tried to use a a loophole. But just to,
you know, put that point home. Um,
yeah. So, that's
>> So, so if you could look in the eye any
of my colleagues or, you know, other
providers that are thinking about
tomorrow starting to prescribe these
non-FDA approved peptides, what would be
the take-home message that you would
tell them? Yeah, don't do it unless
you're you're willing to assume a lot of
risk. Put your license on the line and
also put yourself and your practice and
your business on the line. Um, hold
tight. I would say if you if this really
is where you want to make your stand,
then uh you know, lobby the FDA, go dig
into the science and you know, go talk
to representatives, but don't put your
as it currently stands as of the
recording of this episode. Uh more
guidance is needed unless you want to
put your license on the line.
>> That's what I tell my colleagues and
patients as well every day. I say,
"Look, I I can't tell you which of these
non-FDA approved peptides work or don't
work. I'm not saying they work or they
don't work. I don't have the medical
studies in humans to tell you if they
work or don't work and what population
they would work in versus one that they
wouldn't. So, we just don't have the
information. So, it's not worth the
medical license to do so. There are
plenty other ways that we can, you know,
improve people's health without
resorting to to presently what are known
as research chemicals. So, what patients
do on their own, that's that's on them.
But what these doctors are getting and
what the patients are getting, there's
really not any difference. you know,
they can they can claim, well, I've got
it from a special pharmacy and it's much
better than what you're g. No, they're
not. No, they're not. They're not.
>> Yeah.
>> So, uh
>> and
>> so, but I really appreciate you sharing
your knowledge with us today and I know
you're going to be doing some lectures
uh coming up for for Whirlink Medical
and that's going to be wonderful. I
think that uh that we as physicians
sometimes we we get busy in our
practice. we don't always, you know,
understand the uh the consequences of
some of our actions and uh especially
when it comes to to doing along
something like these peptides because if
everybody's doing it, it must be okay.
That that's kind of the the attitude
they take and they certainly should be a
little bit more cautious when it comes
to these drugs.
>> I would agree. I I don't enjoy being the
party pooper. I usually like to have
the, you know, the workaround, the
exception, the, you know, something that
I can give a lot of the prospective
clients in this category. But a lot of
what that advice has centered around is
okay, what you're doing is technically
illegal. How severe are the consequences
and what does enforcement look like?
Which effectively you're going against
legal advice. We're approaching, you
know, what I might consider a criminal
defense attorney needed, but um that's
the value that I'm offering now. And uh
a lot of people aren't thrilled with
what I say, but uh largely I'm just
regurgitating what federal law says. I'm
breaking it down. Read the blogs. Uh I
always welcome feedback if uh I I'll
I'll try and circle around the comments
for this episode, too. But uh I take a
very conservative reading of the rules.
I will also say uh just this last week
um I had a well more of a we'll just say
prospective client um get a large amount
of um unapproved peptides effectively
seized at customs. So they're sitting on
a ship right now. They'll probably be
destroyed and we'll see I mean what what
they need to do. it wouldn't be
something that I would work with, but
the FDA is starting to seize unapproved
peptides that are coming in through, you
know, China, Korea, wherever at the
border, and that is starting to become a
um a bigger enforcement priority. That
again is not a fun place to be because
not only do you lose all the money that
you use to try and work around the US uh
pharmacies that are not allowed to do
that, now you could potentially face
federal prosecution. So, uh, just
another thing that I remembered from
last week.
>> Well, let let me reiterate this is not
anything anti-eptide. Those peptides
have got to be approved are miracle and
wonderful drugs. I am propeptid. Uh,
what I'm trying to do is help protect my
colleagues from themselves sometimes.
And, uh, you know, once again, if a
person has a problem with it, like you
say, it could be criminal, civil, and
deal with your medical boards. So, who
wants to who wants to have to deal with
that? Well, David, I cannot thank you
enough for coming on and uh providing us
with this valuable information that
you've given us today. Uh I just I hope
it helps so many providers or at least
makes them think twice before they do
anything to potentially harm not only
their reputation but once again face any
criminal uh civil or even even board uh
actions. So if people want to learn more
uh like I said, I refer your website to
every one of my patients that ask about
peptides. Now I say this is this is all
correct information that that that Mr.
Mr. Holt has on his website. Please go
read it and you understand why I can't
write you a prescription for PPC127 or
CJC1295. So this is why I can't do it.
And they all seem to be very
understanding. I didn't know that, doc.
Nobody told me. Everybody's doing it. I
see all over the YouTube and Tik Tok and
Instagram. And I said, I know, but I I
know you do. But uh but nonetheless,
David, if people want to get in touch
with you or if they want to learn more,
how can we go about doing that?
>> It' probably be my website. So that's
the one with the blog you referenced.
It's just a djholtlaw.com
and uh in the search function or if you
say DJ Holtaw peptide it'll pro the the
blogs that you want will probably be the
top two search results. Uh I will note
we work with the healthcare providers uh
not the patients but we we always strive
and we're happy to have anyone read our
resources and we do a really good job of
keeping those uh updated as guidance
comes out. And I'll just say from a
personal perspective, not an attorney
perspective, I am very optimistic for
what we could do with peptides in the
health and wellness space being a a big
wellness guy myself and benefiting quite
a bit from supplements and uh you know
working on my own health individually.
So I I am a big fan. I I just from a
legal perspective that's my my
allegiances to my license which
therefore is federal and state law. So
>> happy to have people visit the blog.
>> Well, I couldn't agree with you more and
once again my perspective is that I want
doctors to be able to prescribe it in
the future whenever it's uh legal and we
have all the studies and and they're not
putting their license at risk. So, thank
you once again for coming on. I think
it's going to be valuable information.
and uh it's been valuable information
for me and I'm sure it's going to be for
many others. So, thank you once again.
>> Thank you. Appreciate it.